Clement Fung

Email: <u>clementf@andrew.cmu.edu</u> Website: <u>https://clementfung.github.io/</u>

SUMMARY

My research interests are at the intersection of machine learning, security, and systems. I have had a particular interest in two major topics: (1) attacks and defenses for multi-party machine learning systems such as Google's federated learning and (2) machine learning security applied to the industrial internet of things.

PUBLICATIONS

Refereed publications

• The Limitations of Federated Learning in Sybil Settings

Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh.

To appear at the 23rd International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions and Defenses (RAID 2020)

Donostia/San Sebastian, Spain (Converted to virtual conference), October 2020.

• Brokered Agreements in Multi-Party Machine Learning

Clement Fung, Ivan Beschastnikh.

 $\overline{10th~ACM~SIG}OPS~Asia-Pacific~Workshop~on~Systems~(APSys~2019)$

Hangzhou, China, August 2019.

• GainForest: Scaling Climate Finance for Forest Conservation using Interpretable Machine Learning on Satellite Imagery

David Dao, Catherine Cang, Clement Fung, Ming Zhang, Nick Pawlowski, Reuven Gonzales,

Nick Beglinger, Ce Zhang.

Climate Change: How Can AI Help?: ICML 2019 Workshop

Long Beach, CA, June 2019.

Non-refereed publications

- Biscotti: A Ledger for Private and Secure Peer-to-Peer Machine Learning. Muhammad Shayan, Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. arXiv November 2018.
- Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting.

 Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh. arXiv November 2018.
- Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning.
 Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. arXiv August 2018.

EDUCATION

PhD, Societal Computing

August 2019 - present

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Cumulative QPA: 4.17 Supervisor: Prof. Lujo Bauer

Research:

- DOM-XSS-ML: Investigating the use of machine learning as a real-time augmentation to traditional taint tracking systems for detecting DOM-XSS.
- ICS-ML: Investigating the use of machine learning for defending and explaining cyber-attacks on industrial control systems.

Graduate Courses:

- 18-730 Introduction to Comptuer Security (*Prof. Virgil Gligor*)
- 18-739F Security and Fairness of Deep Learning (Prof. Piotr Mardziel)

MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting.
 Supervisor: Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh

Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data
- DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

Graduate Courses:

- CPSC 532R Graphical Models (*Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh*)
- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (Prof. Andrew Warfield)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 536F Algorithmic Game Theory (*Prof. Hu Fu*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)

BASc, Honours Systems Design Engineering, Dean's Honour's List Distinction 2011 - 2016 University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Capstone Project:

• Driven: A Automated System for Intelligent Annotation and Analysis of Lane Change Sentiment Supervisor: Prof. Alexander Wong

Awards:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency, 2016
- GM Canada Innovation Award, 2016 \$500
- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, 2015 \$500

- President's International Experience Award, 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award for Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report, 2013 \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, 2011 \$2000

Achievements:

- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant Sept 2016 - Dec 2018

University of British Columbia

• DSCI 571: Supervised Learning
Instructors: Mikchael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar

• DSCI 523: Data Wrangling
Instructors: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti

Fall 2018

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning Winter 2018
Instructor: Michael Gelbart

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Instructor: Mark Schmidt

Fall 2017

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Winter 2017
Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Fall 2016
Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer January 2019 - July 2019

Oasis Labs, Berkeley, CA, USA

• Applications for secure data sharing and other confidential protocols in an early stage blockchain

Research Assistant January 2017 - December 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

• Research on security of machine learning in the Networks, Systems and Security (NSS) Lab.

Software Engineering Intern

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics: Building infrastructure for online relevance scoring at scale

Software Engineering Intern September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Prototyped and designed new derived data serving system, Venice

Software Engineering Intern

January 2014 - April 2014

June - August 2015

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

• Server and Tools: Implemented layer for concurrent database access on a mobile service

Software Developer

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

Software Developer

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

QA Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON